Finding Aid for Frank Angelo (1914- ), Papers 1941-1995
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Frank Angelo Papers 1941-1995
Angelo, Frank.
16 linear feet
Managing editor of the Detroit Free Press, president of the Michigan Press Association, 1969, and national treasurer of Sigma Delta Chi, professional journalism society. Activities and topical files; speeches; papers concerning work on Cooley High School Community Council, Detroit, Michigan, files concerning Detroit race relations and the Detroit riot of 1967; papers relating to Detroit Press Club; and photographs.
85652 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Frank Angelo (donor no. 4996 ) beginning first in 1970. Periodic additions have been received since then.
The collection is open for research.
Frank Angelo was born on September 6, 1914, in Detroit, the son of Italian immigrants. Angelo graduated from Wayne State University in 1934 and began work at the Detroit News. He started as a copy boy, advancing to become a copy editor and sports reporter.
In 1941 Angelo joined the Detroit Free Press, where he worked in the sports department until entering the navy in October 1942. After his discharge in 1945, Angelo returned to the Free Press. He became feature editor in 1950 and managing editor in 1955. During the time Angelo was the managing editor, the Detroit Free Press won a Pulitzer Prize for its coverage of the 1967 Detroit riots. In 1971 he was named associate executive editor and began writing his column. Angelo retired from the Detroit Free Press in 1981, but continued to write throughout his retirement.
Angelo has been an active and influential member of several professional organizations. He was national president of the Society of Professional Journalists, Sigma Delta Chi, (1967-1970) and president of the Michigan Press Association. He has written several books including, Yesterday's Detroit, and Yesterday's Michigan, and has received many journalism honors.
Angelo has also been an active member in many philanthropic and community organizations as well as social agencies in Detroit throughout his life. These include the Detroit Science Center, the Detroit Executive Service Corps, the International Institute, and United Community Services.
The Frank Angelo papers document his career in journalism, as editor of the Detroit Free Press, his professional and community activities. The Angelo papers came to the library in several accession which have been integrated in this description.
Subjects:
Afro-Americans--Michigan.; Angelo, Frank.; Cooley High School (Detroit, Mich.); Detroit (Mich.); Detroit Free Press.; Detroit Press Club.; Riots--Michigan--Detroit.; Journalists--Michigan--Detroit.; Michigan Press Association.; American newspapers--Michigan--Detroit.; Sigma Delta Chi.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Subjects - Visual Material:
African Americans--Michigan--Detroit.; Angelo, Frank.; Arnett, Judd, 1911-; Bursley, Gilbert E.; Chrysler, Richard.; Cleary College (Ypsilanti, Mich.); Eliot, Sonny.; McCarthy, J. P. (Joseph Priestly), 1933-1995.; Roasts (Public speaking); Street-railroads--Michigan--Detroit.; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975.; Williams, G. Mennen, 1911-1988.; Adult education--Michigan--Detroit.; Automobile industry--Michigan.; Automobiles--Michigan.; Battle Creek (Mich.); Business enterprises--Michigan--South Haven.; Business enterprises--Michigan--Detroit.; Detroit (Mich.); Houghton (Mich.); Lone Ranger (Radio program); Fred Sanders (Firm); Lumber industry--Michigan.; Old Newsboys' Goodfellow Fund (Detroit, Mich.); Penobscot Building (Detroit, Mich.); Radio broadcasting--Michigan--Detroit.; Sault Sainte Marie (Mich.); Schools--Michigan--Detroit.; South Haven (Mich.); Television broadcasting--Michigan--Detroit.; Upper Peninsula (Mich.); Vernor's, Inc.; Spina, Tony.
Subjects - Sound Recordings
Angelo, Frank.; American newspapers--Michigan--Detroit.; Journalists--Michigan--Detroit.
Genre/Form:
Photographs.; Sound recordings.; Videotapes.
- Biographical/Personal materials
  The Personal Series sheds light on Angelo's impact on Detroit and Michigan. The correspondence file includes letters from various people which have been influential in the history of Detroit, many notes regarding various awards Angelo received throughout his career and his retirement. The Frank Angelo Tribute/Awards file contains materials and miscellaneous awards which illustrate Angelo's impact on the city, and the greater journalism community. The Navy file contains copies of the official documentation of Angelo's time in the Navy from 1941-1945. There are also materials relating to Angelo's induction into the Michigan Journalism Hall of Fame in 1987, including correspondence, a copy of his speech with notations, newsclippings, and a program from the event.
  - Biographical materials (Box 1)
  - Oral interviews (Box 1)
  - Awards (Box 1)
  - Biography 1914-1981 (Box 12)
  - Death of Mother (1971) (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, bulk of letters from notable people offering congratulations on various awards, circa 1950-1991 (Box 16)
  - Frank Angelo Tribute/awards, certificates, awards, circa 1952-1993 (Box 16)
  - Michigan Journalism Hall of Fame, speech, correspondence, news clippings, program 1987 (Box 16)
  - Navy 1941-1945 (Box 16)
- Correspondence
  - 1970 (Box 1)
  - 1971, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - 1972, 13 folders (Box 1)
  - 1973, 11 folders (Box 1)
  - 1974, 13 folders (Box 1)
  - 1975, 11 folders (Box 2)
  - 1976, 8 folders (Box 2)
  - 1977, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - 1978 (Box 2)
  - 1979, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - 1980, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Undated (Box 14)
  - 1963-1971 (Box 14)
  - January-July 1972 (Box 14)
  - August 1972-1973 (Box 14)
  - 1974-1975 (Box 14)
  - 1976 (Box 14)
  - January-July 1977 (Box 14)
  - August-December 1977 (Box 14)
  - January-August 1978 (Box 14)
  - September-December 1978 (Box 14)
  - January-June 1979 (Box 14)
  - July-December 1979 (Box 14)
  - 1980 (Box 14)
  - 1981 (Box 14)
- Detroit Free Press
  The Detroit Free Press series includes correspondence, topical files and reports relating to management of the newspaper and its role in the community. The series contains files on the 1967-1968 negotiations with the Newspaper Guild and strike, a 1961 report on women's attitudes toward the paper and analysis of the paper's readership.
  - API seminars
    - Undated (Box 2)
    - 1962 (Box 2)
  - Action Line, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Advertising
    - 1958 study (Box 2)
    - 1960s (Box 2)
  - Art (Box 2)
  - Art and Photo Department
    - Personnel (Box 2)
  - Audit Department (Box 2)
  - Circulation (Box 2)
  - City Desk
    - General (1956-1967) (Box 2)
    - Women (Box 2)
  - Comics (Box 2)
  - Conflict of interest policy (Box 2)
  - Daniels, Derick (Box 2)
  - Deadlines (Box 2)
  - Detail of expenses (Box 2)
  - Detroit Magazine-Comment letters (Box 2)
  - Editorial Department
    - Chart (Box 2)
    - Expenses
      - 1950s (Box 2)
      - 1964-1966 (Box 2)
    - Budget 1966 (Box 2)
    - Payroll (Box 3)
  - Editorial policy (Box 3)
  - Elections
    - 1961-1966 (Box 3)
    - 1972 (Box 3)
    - 1980 (Box 3)
  - Expense accounts (Box 3)
  - Features
    - Undated (Box 3)
    - 1950s (Box 3)
    - 1960-1962 (Box 3)
    - 1967-1969 (Box 3)
    - 1970s (Box 3)
  - Ideas of changes (1950s) (Box 3)
  - King Features proposal (Box 3)
  - Litigation, reporting of (Box 3)
  - Management meetings (Box 3)
  - Minority hiring (Box 3)
  - News space increase (Box 3)
  - Newspaper Guild
    - Negotiations 1967-1968
      - Contract proposal November 1967 (Box 3)
      - Publisher's proposal, (November 1967) (Box 3)
      - Angelo's notes (November 1967-July 1968) (Box 3)
      - Minutes November 1967-July 1968, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Memos (December 1967-March 1968) (Box 3)
      - Settlement proposal (July 1968) (Box 3)
      - Positions of Guild (Box 3)
      - Reference material (Box 3)
      - Unfair Labor Practice charge (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - 1969 (Box 3)
    - 1970-1972 (Box 3)
  - Organizational charts (Box 3)
  - Pentagon papers (Box 3)
  - Personnel 1950s-1971, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Photos-color (Box 3)
  - Policy and Procedures Manual (Box 3)
  - Production Handbook (Box 3)
  - Readership
    - Analysis (Box 3)
    - Surveys (Box 3)
    - Comparison with Detroit News (Box 3)
  - Second Front Page (Box 3)
  - Space counts (Box 3)
  - Sports (Box 3)
  - State Desk (Box 3)
  - Strike (post-strike start-up) [2 folders] (Box 3)
  - Suburban coverage
    - 1956-1957 (Box 3)
    - 1958 (Box 3)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 3)
    - 1962 (study) (Box 3)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - Sunday edition (Persky) (Box 3)
  - Sunday Roto Magazine (Box 3)
  - Surveys (1965) (Box 3)
  - Typography (Box 3)
  - Vietnam mail call (Box 3)
  - Washington Bureau (Box 3)
  - Weather (Box 3)
  - West state (Box 3)
  - Women
    - Report on Women's Attitudes (1961) (Box 3)
    - Detroit Women and the Free Press: A Research Report (1961) (Box 3)
  - Women's section (Box 3)
  - Work stoppages (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous memos and correspondence
    - Undated, 1955-1965 (Box 3)
    - 1966-1973 (Box 3)
  - Drafts of articles and supporting material (sample) (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Budget 1966-1969 (Box 12)
  - Convention 1968 (Box 12)
  - Circulation Statistics 1969-1971 (Box 12)
  - Editorial Reports 1963-1972, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Financial Section (Box 12)
  - Intern Program (Box 12)
  - Long Weekends, Planning for (Box 12)
  - Policy and Procedures Manual 1961 (Box 12)
  - Production Schedules 1967-1977 (Box 12)
  - Promotion 1953-1966 (Box 12)
  - Research 1956-1966 (Box 13)
  - Space Allotment 1954-1966 (Box 13)
  - Special Sections 1960-1970 (Box 13)
  - Syndication 1968-1970 (Box 13)
  - Teen Page 1965-1966 (Box 13)
  - Television and Radio 1961-1967 (Box 13)
- Knight Newspapers
  - Seaview Editors Conference October 1970 (Box 4)
  - Report on editorials (Box 4)
  - Editorial reports (1971)
    - Charlotte News (Box 4)
    - Charlotte Observer (Box 4)
    - Detroit Free Press (Box 4)
    - Macon Telegraph and Macon News (Box 4)
    - Miami Herald (Box 4)
    - Philadelphia Daily News (Box 4)
    - Philadelphia Inquirer (Box 4)
    - Tallahassee Democrat (Box 4)
  - News reports
    - Akron Beacon Journal (Box 4)
  - Executives (Box 4)
  - Miami Herald 1971 (Box 13)
  - Minority Recruitment (Box 13)
- Professional Organizations and Activities
  - American Society of Newspaper Editors (Box 13)
  - Associated Press Managing Editors Association (Box 13)
  - Detroit Press Club (Box 13)
  - Key Biscayne Editors Conference 1971 (Box 13)
  - Midwest Journalism History Conference 1981 (Box 13)
  - Newspaper Guild of Detroit 1971 (Box 13)
  - Sigma Delta Chi 1970-1981 (Box 13)
  - World Press Institute 1970 (Box 13)
- Sigma Delta Chi
  - Agnew, Spiro T. (Box 4)
  - Association for Education in Journalism (Box 4)
  - Awards Dinner 1970 (Box 4)
  - By-laws, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Careers committee (Box 4)
  - Campus affairs, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - (Committee) Freedom of Information, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Committees (Box 4)
  - Directories 1968-1974 (Box 4)
  - Endowment Fund (Box 4)
  - Film (Box 4)
  - Finances (Box 4)
  - Foundation (Box 4)
  - General information (Box 4)
  - Historic Sites (Box 4)
  - Installations (Box 4)
  - International (Box 4)
  - Key Biscayne (Box 4)
  - Barney Kilgore award (Box 4)
  - Manual for Regional Directors of Sigma Delta Chi (Box 4)
  - Manual for the Organization of SDX Professional Chapters (Box 4)
  - Membership Eligibility Guidelines (Box 4)
  - Minorities in Journalism, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Minutes (Box 4)
  - Nominations (Box 4)
  - Officers and Executive Councilors manual (Box 4)
  - Oklahoma City: Awards Banquet (Box 4)
  - Publicity Committee (Box 4)
  - Quill (Box 4)
  - Regions (Box 4)
  - Region One (Box 4)
  - Region Three (Box 4)
  - Replate (Box 5)
  - Reports (Box 5)
  - Research (Box 5)
  - Resolutions, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Speeches, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Teacher Award (Box 5)
  - Trips (Box 5)
  - Ways and Means (Box 5)
  - Sigma Delta Chi Conventions
    - 1968 (Box 5)
    - 1969, 4 folders (Box 5)
    - 1970, 8 folders (Box 5)
    - 1971, 4 folders (Box 5)
- Michigan Press Association
  - 1963-1974, 8 folders (Box 5)
  - By-laws 1956, 1967 (Box 5)
  - Committees 1968-1969 (Box 6)
  - Committee minutes 1966-1968 (Box 6)
  - Committee minutes 1969-1973 (Box 6)
  - Financial statements (Box 6)
  - Freedom of Information Committee, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Journalism Building-Michigan State University (Box 6)
  - Papers 1969 (Box 6)
  - Papers 1970-1971 (Box 6)
  - Seminars-Kerner report 1969 (Box 6)
- Detroit Press Club
  - Board of Governors minutes (Box 6)
    - 1962-1970 (Box 6)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Budgets (Box 6)
  - Foundation
    - Correspondence 1965-1967 (Box 6)
    - Directories 1965, 1967 (Box 6)
    - Recommendations (Box 6)
  - Miscellanea (Box 6)
- Civic Organization / Activities
  Angelo was involved in many organizations throughout his career and after his retirement. Many of these are documented in the Civic Organizations/Activities series. Angelo often wrote publicity materials and/or edited official business for many of these organizations. In this series, there are many examples of his writing as well. He served on the Board of Trustees for many organizations which are documented in this series, including the Detroit Science Center, the International Institute, and the Children's Museum. Angelo was also active in the Hand in Hand church group, the Community House of Birmingham organization, and had an interest in Entropic Technologies Corporation. Included in the Entropic Technologies subseries is the Michigan state legislative report on entropic waste management, newsclippings, correspondence, and drafts of a brochure Angelo worked on.
  - International Institute
    - Activities (Box 6)
    - Agency Staff Compensation Program (Box 6)
    - American Council for Nationalities Service (Box 6)
    - Arab-Chaldean Community (Box 6)
    - Archives (Box 6)
    - Associate Director (Box 6)
    - Audits
      - 1978 (Box 6)
      - 1979 (Box 6)
    - Board (general) (Box 6)
    - Board meetings
      - 1972-1979 (Box 6)
      - 1980 (Box 6)
    - Budget
      - 1975 (Box 6)
      - 1978 (Box 6)
      - 1979, 2 folders (Box 6)
      - 1980 (Box 6)
    - By-laws (Box 6)
    - Capital funds (Box 6)
    - Capital improvements (Box 6)
    - Committees (Box 6)
    - Correspondence and memos
      - Undated, September-November 14, 1979 (Box 6)
      - November 16-November 30 1979 (Box 6)
      - December 1979-February 1980 (Box 6)
      - March 1980 (Box 6)
      - April-June, 1980 (Box 6)
    - Director (Box 6)
    - Ethnic Festival (Box 6)
    - Fees and services (Box 6)
    - Food service (Box 6)
    - Friends of the International Institute (Box 6)
  - Institute services
    - Long Range Planning Committee (Box 7)
    - Members Council (Box 7)
    - Membership (Box 7)
    - Nominating Committee (Box 7)
    - Old World Market
      - 1977 (Box 7)
      - 1979 (Box 7)
    - Orientation for Board and Council Members (Box 7)
    - Personnel (Box 7)
    - Publications (Box 7)
    - United Community Services (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - International Visitors Council
    - Weekly reports
      - June-December 1974 (Box 7)
      - January 1975-February 1976 (Box 7)
      - August 1976-August 1977 (Box 7)
      - September 1977-May 1978 (Box 7)
    - General report 1974 (Box 7)
    - Finances
      - 1974 (Box 7)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 7)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 7)
    - Board meetings
      - 1973 (Box 7)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 7)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 7)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence
      - 1974-1976 (Box 7)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 7)
    - Communiques (Box 7)
    - Newsletters (Box 7)
    - Fundraising
      - 1973 (Box 7)
      - 1974 (Box 7)
      - 1975 (Box 7)
      - 1976 (Box 7)
    - Nominations (Box 7)
    - Executive Director (Box 7)
    - COSERV
      - Midwest Conference 1976-1977, 2 folders (Box 7)
      - National Conference 1975 (Box 7)
      - National Conference 1978, 2 folders (Box 7)
      - Board of Directors
        - 1974-1975 (Box 7)
        - 1975-1976 (Box 7)
      - African trip 1977, 2 folders (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Papers
      - 1970-1971 (Box 7)
      - 1972 (Box 7)
      - 1973 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Family Service of Detroit and Wayne County
    - Board of Directors (Box 8)
    - Committees (Box 8)
    - Family Trouble Clinic (Box 8)
    - Finances (Box 8)
    - Nominating Committee (Box 8)
    - Police Referral Project (Box 8)
    - Seminar on Short Term Crisis Treatment (Box 8)
    - UCS program review (Box 8)
    - Papers undated, June 1978-April 1979, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Board Members Manual, 1 volumes (Box 8)
  - Metropolitan Area Planning Committee
    - Minutes (Box 8)
    - By-laws (Box 8)
    - UCS policy statements (Box 8)
    - Recreation Committee, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Recreation study, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Papers
      - 1971-March 1972 (Box 8)
      - April 1972 (Box 8)
      - May-August 1972 (Box 8)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 8)
  - Franklin-Wright Settlements
    - Board of Trustees 1978-1980 (Box 8)
    - Parent-Child Center proposal (Box 8)
    - Career Planning Club (Box 8)
    - Financial statements (Box 8)
    - Long Range Planning Project: Final Report March 1980 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
    - Annual Report 1977, 1 volumes (Box 8)
  - Cooley High School Community Council
    - Correspondence 1965, 1969-1971 (Box 8)
    - Memos (Box 8)
    - Minutes 1969-1970 (Box 8)
    - Policy material (Box 8)
    - Members list (Box 8)
    - Cooley situation-1969
      - Papers (Box 8)
      - Commentary (Box 8)
    - Newsletter (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Mount Carmel Mercy Hospital
    - Correspondence and memos 1978-1979 (Box 9)
    - Executive Board
      - 1972-1973 (Box 9)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 9)
    - By-laws (Box 9)
    - Finances (Box 9)
    - Development Committee report (Box 9)
    - Long Range Master Plan (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Boys Republic
    - Board of Directors
      - Undated, 1971 (Box 9)
      - 1972-1978 (Box 9)
      - 1979 (Box 9)
      - January-February 1980 (Box 9)
      - April-September 1980 (Box 9)
      - Agency manual (Box 9)
    - By-laws (Box 9)
    - Financial statements-1970 1971 (Box 9)
    - Contract with Michigan Federation of Teachers (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - Quality of Work Life
    - Conference January 1979 (Box 9)
    - Board meeting October 1979 (Box 9)
    - Wayne State University termination of support (Box 9)
    - UAW-Paid education leave
      - General Motors (Box 9)
      - Reports and surveys (Box 9)
  - Team for Justice
    - Probation Services Project 1974-February 1975, 5 folders (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Organizations
    - Adcraft Club of Detroit (Box 13)
    - American Society of Newspaper Editors (Box 13)
    - Boys Republic (Box 13)
    - Close-up
      - Contributions
        - 1976-March 1979 (Box 13)
        - April 1979-1981 (Box 13)
      - Correspondence
        - Undated (Box 13)
        - 1971-1978 (Box 13)
        - 1979-1981 (Box 13)
      - Detroit
        - Undated (Box 13)
        - 1976-1981 (Box 13)
      - Funding and Finances
        - 1974-1975, 1978-1979 (Box 13)
      - Printed Materials
        - 1972-1978 (Box 13)
        - 1979-1981 (Box 13)
      - Review
        - 1975 (Box 13)
        - 1976-1977 (Box 13)
        - 1977 (Box 13)
        - 1978 (Box 13)
        - 1979-1980 (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
    - Detroit Area Inter-ethnic Studies Association 1971 (Box 13)
    - Detroit Athletic Club 1979 (Box 13)
    - Detroit Children's Book Fair Council 1975-1981 (Box 13)
    - Detroit Goals 1970-1971 (Box 13)
    - Detroit Historical Society (Box 14)
    - Detroit Renaissance 1970 (Box 14)
    - Economic Club of Detroit 1953-1966 (Box 14)
    - Family Service of Detroit and Wayne County 1975-1981 (Box 14)
    - Franklin-Wright Settlements 1980-1981 (Box 14)
    - International Institute
      - 1980 (Box 14)
      - 1981 (Box 14)
    - International Visitors Council of Metropolitan Detroit 1972-1981 (Box 14)
    - Mackenzie Honor Society 1976 (Box 14)
    - Mayor's Committee for the Cultural Center 1968 (Box 14)
    - Tour-Detroit 1979 (Box 14)
    - United Community Services 1980 (Box 14)
    - Community House, fund drive materials, correspondence, financial reports, news clippings 1984-1985 (Box 15)
    - Detroit Executive Service Corps, correspondence, newsletters, etc. 1987-1992 (Box 15)
    - Detroit Free Press, memos about telling the strike story, other materials relating to the Free Press strikes of the 1950s (notations on material undated), 1956-1968 (Box 15)
    - Entropic Technologies, Michigan state legislative report, news clippings, correspondence, drafts of brochure, etc. 1989 (Box 15)
    - Hand in Hand, (church group program scripts, notes, programs) 1994 (Box 15)
    - International Institute 1986-1992, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Journalism education, course evaluations from journalism course Angelo taught at the University of Michigan 1976 (Box 15)
    - Newspaper Clippings, circa 1950-1990, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - United Community Services 1986-1987, 3 folders (Box 16)
      (materials relating to study of leisure time relating to youth, notes, research, outlines, meeting minutes)
- Speeches
  - Undated, 1955-1976 (scattered dates), 9 folders (Box 9)
  - Speech material (Box 9)
- Topical file
  - Alma College-Executive Committee of the President's Club (Box 9)
  - Area Citizens Advisory Committee/Wayne County Community College (Box 9)
  - Associated Press (Box 9)
  - Associated Press "Black News" Committee, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Associated Press Managing Editors Association (Box 10)
    - Guidelines-1969 (Box 10)
    - Membership (Box 10)
    - Personnel (Box 10)
  - Association for Education in Journalism "Blacks in Journalism", 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Beverage deposit law (Box 10)
  - Bicentennial, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Black and White reporter (Box 10)
  - Book Fair (Box 10)
  - Brand Names Policy (Box 10)
  - Breast Cancer Research Association (Box 10)
  - Cable Television (Box 10)
  - Calvin Presbyterian Church, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Canadian media (Box 10)
  - Citizens Action Committee (Box 10)
  - Clemmons, Geraldine (Box 10)
  - Close-Up Political Education Program (Box 10)
  - Comprehensive Health Planning Council of S.E. Michigan-Virginia Wilkes care (Box 10)
  - Concerned Citizens of Cass Corridor (Box 10)
  - Contests (Box 10)
  - Correspondents list (Box 10)
  - Cranbrook Writers Conference (Box 10)
  - Detroit-Miscellaneous (Box 10)
  - Detroit Adventure, Inc (Box 10)
  - Detroit Ethnic Festival (Box 10)
  - Detroit Historical Society, 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Detroit Metropolitan Airport (Box 10)
  - Detroit Port Development Corporation (Box 10)
  - Detroit school integration-1964 (Box 10)
  - Detroit social agencies-Research reports 1977 (Box 10)
  - Editor-in-Residence Program (Box 10)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica (Box 10)
  - Ethnic Conference 1970 (Box 10)
  - Ethnic material-miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Ethnic newspapers (Box 10)
  - Ethnic studies (Box 10)
  - FOCUS, Inc (Box 10)
  - Fiction (Box 10)
  - Football Green (Box 10)
  - Free press-Fair trial reference file, 5 folders (Box 10)
  - Free press-Michigan State University Teachers' Workshop (Box 11)
  - Free press-miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - Gardening (Box 11)
  - General Motors Business Understanding Contest (Box 11)
  - Governor's Award Commission, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Greater Detroit Council on Alcoholism (Box 11)
  - Highway Safety Center (Box 11)
  - Holmes, David L.-Sports Hall of Fame, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Journalism-Speeches (Box 11)
  - Journalism Schools (Box 11)